DM: technically and more sort of,
DM: I mean, mechanically I think you have.
Delwath: There's not... It's actually true, there's not-
Unknown: There's not a-
Delwath: ... a super clear sense of like-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... the actual relationships between our characters.
Delwath: Like what are they actually-
Kenzo: Well, so I kind of-
Seeker: Like a little rivalry.
Kenzo: Yeah. Well, that's what I was gonna say. I, I was gonna say, so one of the funnest shit was like when, uh, when Seeker and, and um, and Kenzo were, we were like throwing eggs at each other and like kind of fighting and having like little piece of chat like.
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: Or even, or even like, uh, um, Kenzo-
DM: There's the little Kenzo, Ja-
Kenzo: The Kenzo, Delwath thing, which has also like been fun, like the whole-
Unknown: But I think it's-
Kenzo: But yeah, those aren't like-
Delwath: It's, it's lightly developed compared to many other aspects of the-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Yeah
Unknown: ... of the game.
Seeker: Yeah. So we could lean into that more if we want to, to get more of that.
DM: But partly, I, I think that's partly because of the epic scale, right?
DM: It's harder to do that when,
DM: when you're... When the adventures are-
Delwath: See, I think it's partly because we play-
Unknown: Yeah, that's true
Delwath: ... a huge amount of our game between 10:00 PM and midnight-
DM: That's also true
Seeker: ... on a weeknight.
Delwath: I just, I think it's, I find it a lot harder to-
Seeker: Oh, you're just more tired, it's hard for-
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Everybody's tired.
Delwath: It's just, it's easier to think in...
Delwath: It's a lot easier to think as Mike as Delwath than as Delwath.
Seeker: Right.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: And I find it harder to...
Unknown: It's more work.
DM: But that's, I mean, we don't have much choice.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: I mean, at some point everybody's kids will be old enough that we can play at 6:00, but not for a campaign three, maybe campaign four.
Seeker: Yeah. [laughs] It's gonna be a while.
Kenzo: Man, dude, five kids, that's just gonna get all fucked up.
DM: Yeah.
Seeker: But we'll deal with it.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: I appreciate the flexibility, honestly.
Kenzo: No, that's great.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Oh, yeah.
Delwath: Um, so I just think there's certain, there's certain things that are hard to achieve-
DM: Right
Delwath: ... just because of the
Unknown: nature of-
DM: The time, when we can play. Yeah
DM: ... when we play and who we are and just how it, right.
Seeker: Well, role playing feels quite different in person too.
Unknown: Also.
DM: Right. It's nicer in person, for one.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: Uh, the combat is a lot more enjoyable in person.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Mm-hmm.
Wellby: Yeah. I, like I, I feel like that's part of like me dropping last night.
Wellby: Like part of what felt so unpleasant to go down in combat online is like-
Seeker: You can't do anything
Wellby: ... you're just sitting there.
DM: Right.
Wellby: Like there's so little... Like I still felt so engaged in this.
DM: Yes.
DM: You're not as engaged.
Wellby: In a way that it just wasn't...
Delwath: It is true that in-person combat, I mean, that's part of what I think...
Delwath: I was thinking about
Delwath: our most, like almost all of our best combats have been on
Delwath: in person.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: In our in person.
Seeker: I mean, it's partly 'cause Tim plans an even more epic thing than usual.
DM: Right. But it's also just,
DM: it's just a lot easier to run-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... in person because it's not as...
DM: I think there's just also something about having a physical battle map that's-
Delwath: Well, I also think there's something about seeing...
Delwath: There's a lot of like watching what other people roll.
Seeker: Right.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: There's a lot of-
Seeker: That's exciting too, yeah
Delwath: ... like, like every time Seeker was rolling a concentration check.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Oh yeah, that's fun.
Delwath: We're all like watching with bated breath.
Kenzo: Yeah, that's so fun.
DM: That was great.
Delwath: And you lose that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: You lose that when you're online.
Delwath: Because you're not really...
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: I think it's also easier for like side conversations to happen.
DM: Right.
Unknown: Like online-
Seeker: You can't really
Wellby: ... only two people can be talking really.
DM: Right.
Seeker: Yeah. Right.
Wellby: Turn and DM.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: Well,
DM: until we have...
Kenzo: Yeah. Until our neu- our, our neural links and the telepresence, you know.
Seeker: Yeah. When we're all playing Apple Vision Pro.
Seeker: [coughs] Actually, there is an AR platform for gaming.
Seeker: What's that thing called? Have you seen this?
Seeker: It's a former Media Lab person's startup thing.
Delwath: Do, do you know if there's any VTT that rolls dice visibly on the table?
DM: So you can do it in both D&...
DM: You can do it in Roll20. You can roll dice on the table in Roll20.
Kenzo: Oh, really? Where they just show up, where they visibly show up for everybody?
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: I actually think that would be worth trying.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: So I actually thought, I've considered, it's more work, but maybe I'll have time to do it.
DM: Kind...
DM: Looking at other virtual tabletops that might be more
DM: amenable to some of these things.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: Like, because part of the...
DM: One of the things that makes combat s- slow on l- it, what it...
DM: Less engaging because everything's, you know, you're not there, but also, like, there's like a second delay every time you click a button on-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... D&D Beyond before it shows up in Roll20.
DM: I mean, it's, the connection is nice, but it's not perfect, and the...
DM: You know, you just have to go so many places on your character sheet to click things.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: That it kind of slows things down.
Seeker: I kind of hate D&D Beyond.
Seeker: Um, I-
Unknown: I don't like it
Seeker: ... don't feel like I have an alternative, but.
Delwath: D&D Beyond is...
Seeker: It's just, it feels complicated, and it's probably 'cause it is complicated.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: D&D Beyond's complicated.
Delwath: I actually looked at alternatives.
Delwath: I actually, for the game I'm running, I use something called Dice Cloud, which is a alternative.
DM: Hmm.
Delwath: But it's more complicated.
Delwath: It's, it's, it's-
Delwath: Dice Cloud, Dice Cloud is really, really good for home brewing.
DM: You can home brew anything-
Unknown: Mm.
DM: ... super, super easily.
Delwath: But the actual UI is actually worse than D&D Beyond.
Seeker: Right. That's, that's the issue for me is that, like, maybe it's just the nature of my character.
Seeker: There's so many interesting details, some of which are D&D things, some of which are made by Tim that I have to, like, keep track of or look up every-
Delwath: So, I mean, this is the nice thing about Dice Cloud.
Delwath: Dice Cloud is actually, uh, open.
Delwath: I mean, it's, you can run your own dice.
Unknown: Like, it's a JavaScript app.
Seeker: Oh, nice.
Delwath: At one point I was like, I should just fix it.
Delwath: I should just make it... 'Cause it, it does a terrible job of putting the information you want in one spot.
Seeker: Mm.
DM: So Roll20, I mean, Roll20 has a lot of potential for this because you can...
DM: It has a, it has an API.
DM: You can write arbitrary JavaScript code that runs.
Delwath: But, but see, I actually think what you want is something less.
Delwath: To me- What is cool about in person is that you're spending less time looking at your character sheet and more time looking at the combat.
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: D&D Be- like online, you're very encouraged to tune out when other people are-
DM: But what I'm-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... what I would try, the thing that is potentially possible to do is,
DM: um, Kate also hates this because it also is really, if you're only playing on one screen, it's really annoying to have Roll20, D&D Beyond, and DM-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... all up at once.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yep.
DM: So to the extent to which you could move everything to basically just be Roll20.
Seeker: Oh, because that has video conferencing?
DM: The video conferencing used to suck.
DM: It might be better now.
Unknown: Better.
DM: Um, Zo- I mean, Zoom is, the advantage of Zoom is you get the recording and the transcripts.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
Seeker: Have you, have you...
Delwath: Is Discord not good for...?
DM: Well, Isaac uses Discord.
DM: Discord's fine,
DM: but you don't get a transcript.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Mm.
Delwath: But one thing you c- I mean, what you could do is actually do-
Delwath: Just 'cause Discord had DD bots built in.
DM: Right. You could do audio-
Unknown: Uh
DM: ... on Zoom and video on Roll20.
DM: And then you could just-
Seeker: And just run it in the background, yeah
DM: ... then you could just have Zoom minimized in the background.
DM: And
DM: if you could, if you could automate enough things so that it was easy for you to, like, if you had little buttons to, like, it's really annoying, like, to roll dice
DM: in Roll20 that are visual dice.
DM: You have to, like, click on the menu-
Unknown: Click, yeah
DM: ... and then select the dice you want to roll.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: But if you had buttons that were just like D20 with advan- D- two D20, one D20,
DM: you know.
Seeker: Yeah, like favorite dice.
DM: Favorite dice, then you could just click the button and it would roll on the tabletop, and then you would just need,
DM: like, a way to...
DM: But if everybody just used, have your D&D Beyond character sheet on your
DM: phone, if you had to look stuff up.
Unknown: Ooh.
DM: The other option is, like, it's more money, but, like, if, you know, I spend 100 bucks or 120 bucks to buy the books in Roll20 in addition to on D&D Beyond,
DM: then you'd have, you could have all of the spells and stuff just show up as buttons in Roll20, so it would give you the
DM: spell information. You wouldn't have to reference it on your-
Delwath: I actually think the thing that would make
Delwath: combat online, the one thing that would make it more engaging would be to be rolling dice in public on the table.
DM: Right.
Delwath: Quickly. Like, w- ideally with not, like, some super long animation, but with a little bit of an animation.
DM: Yeah, so that-
Unknown: So that you can never really see-
DM: But that's the nice thing about Roll-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... Roll20 is, like, completely custom.
DM: You could, I could, I mean, ChatGPT or Claude or some agent mode could write a script that would generate buttons for common dice combos.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: With animation tunes so that it-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... didn't take-
DM: ... 20 seconds to roll.
Unknown: [clears throat]
DM: It took two seconds to roll.
Seeker: That'd be good.
Kenzo: Eric, sorry, when you say, like, you hate D&D, uh, Beyond, are you talking about the UI or you talking about, like, the whole gaming system in general?
Seeker: D- so D&D Beyond as a user interface to access parts of your character sheet.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I see, I see. Okay.
Wellby: Because everything relevant is in a tiny little tabbed window in a quarter of the screen.
DM: And it's also spread out all over the place.
Seeker: And I need to look, go back and forth between looking at two different things, which means, like, it's-
Unknown: Yep
Seeker: ... five or six clicks.
DM: Yep.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: And so what I end up doing-
DM: Yes
Seeker: ... is, like, instead of looking at my spells inside D&D Beyond, I search for them on Google.
Unknown: Yep.
Seeker: Pull 'em up on some unrelated site, and then-
DM: Right
Seeker: ... open it in a tab, and maybe it's, like, the wrong version of the spell.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: So it's, like, it's terrible.
DM: It is. It's really not great.
DM: Got it, got it, got it.
DM: 'Cause the way, I mean, the, the way the UI desi- is designed with all these, like, pop-ups that, you know, pop-outs from the edge.
DM: But there's, like, so many different tabs you have to click.
DM: You can't get...
Delwath: But it's also-
Seeker: Yeah
Delwath: ... it does a terrible job at...
Delwath: It, it's just, like, I find it impossible to use to keep track of stuff.
Unknown: Like, I always wind up ticking off-
Seeker: Yeah, like the one thing it should do-
Unknown: It should be-
Seeker: ... is help you temporarily check things off.
DM: Correct. [laughs]
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: Quickly during a combat.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: It is awful.
Seeker: And that's the hardest thing to do.
Unknown: Yes.
Seeker: And also it feels unreliable because there's, like, five different ways to cast a spell, and some of them t- check off the spell slots and some don't.
Seeker: And it's like, remember-
DM: Yeah, yeah. No, it's, I tried to-
Seeker: So it doesn't do that at all. [laughs]
DM: Yeah.
Delwath: Right. But then I forget how many sorcery points I've used.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
DM: Right. So that's the other thing about, so you could make buttons in D&D Beyond, I mean in Roll20, that you just click every time you use a key or every time you use a sorcery point, and it just, it just
DM: clicks and it just-
Seeker: Yeah
DM: ... DM-
Delwath: That's kind of what Dice Cloud is actually good at too.
Delwath: Like, I...
Delwath: The Dice Cloud UI is kind of crap.
Seeker: Right.
Delwath: But it's very good at automating.
Delwath: It's like a, a system that makes it easy to automate.
DM: Right. I mean, the one that everybody online says is the best for automation is Foundry.
DM: It's just, um,
DM: it's
DM: really difficult to set up because-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... it's like Dice Cloud. It's like, it has a, it ha- it's a very flexible back end that you can design anything you want in, but
DM: you just have to spend a lot of time setting it up, and then you can automate things.
Seeker: Yeah.
DM: I mean, I do like, the thing I like on Roll20 is, like, the spell templates that let you immediately get the area of a spell-
Seeker: Right
DM: ... without having to spend a long time discussing, like-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... what's in or out.
Wellby: Yeah. I feel like that, that was the one piece of combat that's trickier analog.
DM: Yes.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: Is to be able to just draw up-
DM: Yes
Wellby: ... and reposition-
DM: Right
Unknown: ... radiuses and things.
Seeker: I do like drawing stuff on the map.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: That's fun.
DM: But I think I, I'm gonna, I'm gonna investigate this for-
Delwath: The, the other thing to think about, even the things that feel like, oh, you have to build that.
Delwath: Like, I was like, "Oh, Dice Cloud's gonna be a lot of work," 'cause I switched my game to Dice Cloud because I'd home-brewed.
Unknown: I had
Delwath: home-brewed a custom [coughs] subclass for basically everybody.
Seeker: Right.
Delwath: And like, I just couldn't...
Kenzo: The D&D Beyond home-brewing stuff is just too painful.
Delwath: I couldn't deal with it.
Unknown: So
Delwath: I was like, "Oh, but this is gonna be annoying. I'm gonna have to, like, im- create everything from scratch."
Delwath: But actually you only have to create the stuff from scratch for- ...
Delwath: the things you're actually using, right?
Unknown: So it's actually not that much work.
DM: Yeah, I mean, that's like when I made all the spells in D&D Beyond, it took me
DM: a couple of hours to do all the spells that you could use.
Unknown: Mm-hmm.
DM: It would've taken days to do all the spells-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... in the game.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: But that's what I'm thinking, like if we go back to a, if we do some lower level stuff-
Unknown: If-
DM: ... I can start a fresh-
Unknown: Mm
DM: ... level 20 campaign and just build up the things that are actually-
Unknown: It's relevant
DM: ... needed for the low level campaign, and it's much easier than trying to switch when you're level 20.
Unknown: Yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Yeah, there's too many things.
DM: When you have 100 million things you can do.
Delwath: Right. No, no, for, for these characters-
DM: Yeah
Delwath: ... I wouldn't.
Seeker: How do you think of the role of Taelgarverse in all of this?
Seeker: It's kind of alongside the mechanical stuff.
Unknown: Dude, totally.
Seeker: But we use it all the time as part of the game, which is great.
Seeker: So it's essentially like just an archive of-
DM: [coughs]
Unknown: I mean-
Unknown: ... world
Delwath: ... I was gonna say earlier about the, about the other thing, my actual favorite thing in the game is world building.
Unknown: Mm.
DM: Right.
Seeker: Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Delwath: And even more, I love it when Tim uses my world building in this campaign.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah. Hmm.
Unknown: I think
Wellby: for me, like part of the reality is like s- some of the stuff...
Wellby: I remember, I mean, this is a long time ago now, us walking around in the woods talking about like halfling things in California, right?
Kenzo: Oh, shit, that was awesome.
Kenzo: Like three or four years ago now.
Kenzo: That, that's when we came up with the whole like, uh, like the halflings, they just have one song.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: And like that whole... Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah.
Wellby: And like, and like that's
Wellby: so fun, but also the reality is like
Wellby: I don't set aside time to do that.
Wellby: Uh, like the sessions are sort of like-
Unknown: Right
Wellby: ... are my D&D time.
Unknown: Mm.
Unknown: Like-
Seeker: Right, right, right
Wellby: ... I wonder if there's a way within it to-
DM: So it's tricky.
Unknown: Hmm.
DM: So Mike's players like-
Unknown: Good question
DM: ... spend hours sending each other emails about world building.
DM: The problem with doing it during a session is what's nice about world building is being able to sort of test out ideas without having to commit to something, but it's...
DM: And like explore ideas, and then you figure out what makes sense-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... by talking about it. But-
Unknown: But the-
DM: ... in a session you feel a little bit of pressure to-
Wellby: Move the plot forward.
Seeker: Oh, there is that too.
DM: Well, not just move the plot forward, but to not like be constantly retconning things, right?
Unknown: Right.
DM: So if you, if I like say make up something about halflings, you're sort of on the spot to do something that actually seems perfect in that moment.
Wellby: Yeah. I, so I agree, like when it's, if it's right in, in the middle of like, "You open a door," and meet a halfling, like-
DM: Right
Wellby: ... tell me about the role of like bar keepers and [laughs] half-
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Like,
Wellby: but there's gotta be other ways to do that.
Wellby: Like, what if that's the warm-up before the session starts?
Unknown: Mm.
Wellby: Like, we have like-
DM: Right
Wellby: ... 30 minutes of world building and three questions.
DM: I mean, that's great if you all would actually join the Zoom at 8:00.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It's just, we just have so...
DM: There's just not very much time, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: So like already we often-
Seeker: But we could devote part of the time to that.
Wellby: But also, like if-
Unknown: If we want to do that
Wellby: ... if the goal is enjoying ourselves-
DM: Yeah, yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... and this is as enjoyable as moving the thing forward, like we-
DM: I mean-
DM: No, no, no, I get that. I think-
Delwath: Making up the Maw or Sentient Ocean was also super fun.
DM: Was awesome. We were just driving around in the Tesla.
DM: We were driving around. Yeah.
Unknown: Making it up.
DM: You guys. So I think the challenge is when you, when se- when you get a session below about three hours, it's tricky because-
Unknown: Yeah
Delwath: ... you either, you basically either can't run a, a combat.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Or it's sort of like, it's hard to sort of have multiple scenes.
DM: And so if you...
Unknown: [coughs]
DM: Now, one thing we could explore is like playing more frequently, but for much shorter times, like two and a half hour sessions
DM: more frequently rather than trying to do three and a half hour sessions less frequently.
DM: Or we could alternate, right? You could have some short sessions and some...
DM: I mean, there's various things we could do.
Delwath: Well, 'cause what, would a, would a shorter session, you would just run one scene a session basically?
DM: You wouldn't, y- it wouldn't matter so much if a combat takes the whole session, right?
DM: It's kind of frustrating if-
Unknown: Hmm
DM: ... anything other than a boss fight, if combat takes the whole time.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But if you're running short, if you're, if you have two hours of gameplay, you can basically run two encounters, or an encounter is a scene, right?
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Like two scenes, right? So you can actually-
Seeker: Part of that's just about speeding up. I mean, I think-
DM: Part of it's speeding combat up
Delwath: ... lower level combat would be way faster, lower level.
Delwath: There's also, there's also work everybody could do.
DM: I know, but I'm not... Like I'm being realistic about the amount of work these Targos.
Delwath: Well, but I actually think there's tool...
Delwath: Like, again, if you look at the tooling, combat would be a lot faster if the mechanism by which everybody was presented with options was-
DM: Was not so-
DM: ... a lot more straightforward.
DM: Yeah. Kate hates that about D&D Beyond.
DM: It's like I can never figure out what I can do because it's on five different tabs.
Unknown: Exactly.
Unknown: This is in a way the same-
Unknown: Yeah
Unknown: ... concern I had.
Delwath: Right. And so if you knew what you can do in combat, right, in a much more condensed way, you would be much more likely to...
Delwath: 'Cause in the ideal situation in combat, it's like actually it moves pretty quickly.
DM: Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right?
Kenzo: Combats are too long, man. Like, so some of the combats, like they dr- they like, I would gladly sacrifice like a big, a big chunk of like the combat time to do like the world building thing.
DM: Yeah.
Kenzo: I would gladly do that.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: But part of the challenge is that D&D is very much structured as a combat system, and so a lot of your character abilities are actually only relevant in combat.
Unknown: Right.
DM: Well, I, I mean, this has not been a very high combat campaign.
Unknown: No.
DM: To me, it's sort of not like, I mean, the...
DM: Fundamentally, you're gonna go explore dungeons and fight dragons, right?
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: That's the name of the game. I mean-
Unknown: That is likely to be involved somewhere.
Delwath: And to me, there's an extent to which, you know, you level up and you get some cool new ability.
Unknown: You wanna use your ability.
DM: And you then wanna use it-
Unknown: Right
Delwath: ... 'cause it's, otherwise it's like...
DM: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: Right? Speaking of long combats, it's 1:00.
Unknown: Right.
Seeker: Oh, I gotta eat some lunch.
DM: Uh-
Delwath: Yeah, we should like-
DM: ... do like Who's to Kill?
Delwath: We should go play D&D instead of talking about this.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: We can talk about it next time.
DM: We can revisit this while we're cooking dinner and-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... watching the sunset and a- you know, during and after the game as well.
Delwath: I mean, what I actually think is interesting, just one thought.
Delwath: What's interesting with this conversation and your desire to not start something, just actually why don't we just ex- like-
DM: We can try a whole bunch of things
Delwath: ... we can try all kinds of different things in the next year, right?
Unknown: Like-
Seeker: Well, the timeline building game, what was that?
DM: Oh, that was fun.
Unknown: Speaking of.
Kenzo: Oh, um, uh, Microscope?
DM: Microscope.
Unknown: Macroscope.
DM: Yeah. Mic- It was called Microscope.
Unknown: Oh.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: [coughs]
Kenzo: Uh, and really quick just 'cause I- I was, I started recording this so later on we can like try to be like, "Hey, what were we talking about?
Unknown: The things we-"
Unknown: Yeah.
Kenzo: So, but, uh, so plot twists.
Kenzo: Uh, like unexpected plot twists are for satisfying-
Seeker: Storytelling mechanics.
Unknown: Stor-
DM: Mm-hmm
Kenzo: ... storytelling mechanics.
Unknown: Where like-
Seeker: Where like you make up things in order to solve problems.
DM: Right.
Kenzo: Right, right. What were the other bits?
Unknown: Does-
DM: Uh-
Wellby: Creepy fairy tale stuff instead of-
DM: Right
Unknown: ... dice stuff.
Delwath: And things where the wrong choice, not the wrong die roll.
Kenzo: Yeah, yeah, yeah. Okay.
Seeker: Mm-hmm. And generally world building is part of-
DM: And world building
Seeker: ... the experience.
Unknown: Right, right.
Seeker: We like. What else? Like
Seeker: fun role playing vignettes.
Kenzo: Yes, with the characters get to do-
Unknown: Yeah
Kenzo: ... like in a fun little-
DM: Yeah. I'm... So actually, I, thinking about, not to distract, but thinking about the warm-ups a little bit.
DM: I did at one point try that, like everybody describe-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... their character warm-up.
DM: Which-
Delwath: It never really worked though
DM: ... well, you guys never really-
Unknown: Right
DM: ... people didn't really do it.
DM: And, and, um-
Wellby: For some reason it wasn't the right thing for us.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Like the first couple of times-
Unknown: They picked at you
Wellby: ... after... And after doing it once or twice, it's sort of like-
DM: But, but actually-
Unknown: It took a little something to get
DM: ... so this, I'm thinking about this, right?
DM: Like, I still don't... I mean, I can picture Wellby and Seeker pretty clearly.
DM: I still can't really picture Kenzo that clearly in my head.
DM: Delwath, I guess Delwath I can sort of fairly easily.
Delwath: Yeah. Well, just look at the mini fig.
Unknown: [laughs] Yeah.
Kenzo: Look, there he is.
Unknown: It's right there.
Kenzo: Nobody knew what-
Unknown: And it's like
Kenzo: ... no- nobody really knew what Kenzo's staff looked like until this trip.
DM: But, but- [laughs]
Unknown: Now we all really understand.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: But what I wanted to say about that is, so I think Eric
DM: a- and Mike to a certain extent really sort of had, you could see how their characters appearance and equipment and stuff changes in the description.
Unknown: [laughs]
DM: Like when you got, Seeker got the glove and the red tolling cloak which became kind of-
Unknown: Iconic
DM: ... iconic.
Seeker: And it, his, his hair care.
DM: Exactly.
Seeker: He has the white streak in the hair.
DM: Right. Whereas, not shade on Calm and Schwartz, but like
DM: the pa- the part of the goal of that like describe your character was so that you could actually incorporate into your description how your character changes over time.
Unknown: Yeah.
DM: It doesn't feel so static.
DM: Right? And-
Unknown: Well it's true because-
DM: And Wellby, you had the thing with the hats
Wellby: ... with, with leopard armor it's just like I'm gonna be different every time.
Unknown: Right.
DM: But I also-
Wellby: Like, there wasn't a progression to it.
Delwath: There's also, it's just, I think there's-
DM: But there could be if you wanted there to be, right?
Delwath: I think there's a certain pressure of a warm-up that doesn't necessarily tie into...
Delwath: I, to me, there was times where I sort of felt like, well, I don't really know what Delwath is doing.
Wellby: Oh, also that warmup isn't collaborative.
Unknown: Right. Right.
Seeker: Ah. So what would be a collaborative warmup, which is like we riff on some world building question that's not part of our characters-
Unknown: Like y-
Seeker: ... or more loosely coupled to what we're doing right now.
Wellby: I mean, I think even with something like you're going into this random town, like, what's, what's it like?
Unknown: What's the vibe? What's the-
Unknown: Oh, that's great
Wellby: ... what's the main business in the town?
Unknown: That's great.
Seeker: Make up seven business names and find-
Unknown: Character.
Kenzo: That's great. I love that
Unknown: ... I guess, yeah.
Kenzo: I love that.
Unknown: I love-
Seeker: And then Tim could take or leave any part of it.
Unknown: But we're-
DM: So that was f- I mean, that was fun when we were developing Malar.
DM: You, I mean, you, everybody made up part of Malar and we sort of riffed on Homary.
DM: But
DM: it's a little bit tricky if that's
DM: from my prep point of view, if we're-
Unknown: Yeah
DM: ... we're going into a town, let's invent the town in the first 30 minutes of the session, and then I'm gonna run an adventure in the town.
DM: [laughs]
Seeker: So, so yeah, the, the task is to somehow bound it so that it fits within your plan.
Kenzo: [coughs] Or, or for two-
Seeker: Like, like on the train-
DM: ... 10 sessions
Seeker: ... in the Cyberpunk adventure where you had us make up the characters with a set of questions about them.
DM: Yeah. Oh yeah. That was really fun actually.
DM: I think... Was that only me and Eric who were there?
Wellby: I have no memory of this.
DM: The, the, the-
Unknown: That's funny.
DM: It was like the bottle episode-
Unknown: There was sequence
DM: ... where we were going on the train-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah, yeah, yeah
DM: ... to Minnesota-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... or Montana or somewhere.
Seeker: And we weren't really on a train at all.
DM: We weren't actually on a train.
Unknown: That's right.
DM: We were like...
Unknown: No, of course not. [laughs]
Seeker: We're, we were being simulated.
Wellby: Yep. That sounds-
Seeker: That was fucked up. That's great.
Delwath: I mean, I, I do think a collaborative
Delwath: relevant world building riff that is not committed to be canonical would be really fun.
Unknown: That's also-
Seeker: But I mean, Tim could take or leave. Yeah.
Unknown: Yeah.
Wellby: But also, like, I mean, it,
Wellby: the riff that we're doing for that doesn't have to be related to the-
DM: Yeah
Kenzo: ... adventure that we're running.
Unknown: Exactly. Exactly.
Wellby: Like it could still be canonical 100 miles away, so that by the time we get there-
DM: Yeah. Yeah, yeah
Wellby: ... there's a built in to incorporate.
Seeker: But I'd love to talk about Dran- Drancor. We're not nowhere near there.
Unknown: Yeah.
Delwath: Or it could be about a character back...
Delwath: I mean, the other thing that's fun is like, well, okay, where was your character
Delwath: 10 years ago today? What was your character doing?
Seeker: Yeah. They never did all that much with Seeker's backstory.
Unknown: Right. And-
DM: Oh.
Unknown: Although-
Seeker: That was one... Franker even exists because of one session.
Unknown: Right. Because of that.
Seeker: What was the mechanic that led to that?
DM: That was-
Delwath: There was one session where Tim was like, "Tell me, just share something about your childhood."
DM: So that was a session where I had-
Unknown: Oh, yeah
DM: ... not really prepped anything, and it was like early on, it was like session 15 or something, and I needed...
DM: I just hadn't gotten around to figuring out what was next, and I didn't wanna just have an hour long session of you meandering around Kerela.
DM: So I, I looked online for like role-playing prompts.
Unknown: Right.
DM: And I was like, we s- as you start the session, you all think back to, I forget what it was, something about your childhood.
Seeker: This is the kind of thing Schw- that, you know, where it says-
Delwath: But I actually think Schwartz's point about collaborative is the key one.
DM: Right.
Delwath: 'Cause I feel like
Delwath: it feels very...
Delwath: The sort of everybody describe your character is very inward.
Unknown: Inward. Yeah.
Delwath: And kind of-
Unknown: Yeah, it's-
Delwath: It's almost like-
DM: It's hard to... It, it's not interactive.
Kenzo: Well, it's gen- it's generative when you can build off of everybody else's-
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Wellby: Let's make a thing together.
Unknown: Yeah.
Seeker: Yeah.
Unknown: I love that.
Unknown: Although-
Seeker: The bouncing off.
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... the childhood stories one was-
Seeker: ... particularly fun.
Delwath: Childhood stories one was fun, but it would actually, to me, have been probably more fun if we had all made up one of Delwath's childhood stories.
Seeker: Something like that. Yeah, yeah, yeah.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: Oh, interesting.
Delwath: Instead of-
Seeker: So we each contribute to each other's characters.
DM: Exactly.
Seeker: 'Cause that's, that's another thing to, that strengthens it, is if we're sort of aware of-
Unknown: Yeah
Seeker: ... and involved with what the other characters are like.
Delwath: Right. Right, like-
Seeker: 'Cause it's easy to get focused on your own.
Delwath: Or if we had all made up a Delwath story and a Kenzo story-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah
Delwath: ... but not all four of them, right?
Unknown: Like-
Unknown: Right
Unknown: ... if-
Wellby: Like, I think it goes back to, like, what you were saying about, like, secrets from each other, too.
Wellby: Like, I remember in that high school campaign, there was so much that was known only to us [laughs] individually.
Delwath: Right. Did, did everybody-
Unknown: Yeah, yeah. Sorry
DM: ... like, I'm gonna get coffee.
Delwath: Did everybody... Coffee, who wants new coffee?
Unknown: I love coffee.
Unknown: Uh, I'm gonna have some coffee.
Delwath: Okay. I just didn't want to take a second cup of-
Unknown: We-
Unknown: But I don't, let's, uh-
Wellby: I don't actually wanna do that anymore.
DM: I, yeah. Anybody who wants to have, make lunch should, like, get some coffee-
Unknown: Right. Yes
Unknown: ... so we can play.
Delwath: I mean, I do sometimes think that plot information distributed out to individual people and then our job is to integrate the knowledge
Delwath: can be fun.
Unknown: Yeah, that-
Unknown: But that's like-
Unknown: Yeah, so I tried to do that in your case-
Unknown: ... a little bit of a task
DM: ... but because of the...
DM: To, for that to really work, we'd all, everybody has to commit to reading something in advance-
Unknown: Yes
DM: ... which is hard to do.
Unknown: Yes.
Delwath: It also works better in person, I think.
Delwath: I've done it a few times successfully when
Delwath: we're gonna take half, when I don't have a lot prepped.
Unknown: Right.
Delwath: And you almost just have handouts, and if people read the handouts at the beginning and then everybody talks about it.
Seeker: I think I saved my-
Delwath: But it's easy for it to be generating, why don't I just forward you the email?
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Right.
Unknown: And then-
Seeker: I saved my, my ooze-based lunch for the perfect moment.
Unknown: [laughs]
Seeker: I'm gonna have mac and cheese, which will be nice and gooey.
Delwath: Um, I think I'm gonna make...
Delwath: Oh, right, I got mozzarella.
DM: Yeah. I'm not...
DM: We might, we might end up having to do the final moment of this after dinner.
Unknown: [laughs]
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: It's already one.
Delwath: Well, we had a whole long...
Unknown: I mean,
Delwath: I think we should-
Wellby: Well, I mean, now that we know we should be efficient in our combat, it'll go much-
Unknown: Maybe I'll be very efficient.
Delwath: Yeah. Well, we...
Delwath: Actually, I think we were pretty efficient in combat last night.
Unknown: We did great last night.
Unknown: Yeah.
Unknown: Great. Um.
Unknown: [dishes clanking]
Unknown: [clears throat] [objects clanking]